This summer a star falls. The chase begins.
Stardust is a adventure, fantasy, romance film directed by Matthew Vaughn.
In a countryside town bordering on a magical land, a young man makes a promise to his
beloved that he'll retrieve a fallen star by venturing into the magical realm.
His journey takes him into a world beyond his wildest
dreams and reveals his true identity.
Tristan Thorn, played by Charlie Cox.
Yvaine, played by Claire Danes.
Lamia, played by Michelle Pfeiffer.
Septimus, played by Mark Strong.
Primus, played by Jason Flemyng.
Captain Shakespeare, played by Robert De Niro.
Stardust is a 2007 romantic fantasy adventure film directed by
Matthew Vaughn and co-written by Vaughn and Jane Goldman.
Based on Neil Gaiman's 1999 novel, it features an ensemble cast led by Claire Danes, Charlie Cox, Sienna Miller, Ricky Gervais,
Jason Flemyng, Rupert Everett, Peter O'Toole, Michelle Pfeiffer and Robert De Niro, with narration by Ian McKellen.
The film follows Tristan, a young man from the
fictional town of Wall in England.
Wall is a town on the border of the magical fantasy kingdom of Stormhold.
Tristan enters the magical world to collect a fallen star to give to his
beloved Victoria, in return for her hand in marriage.
To his surprise, he collects the star, a woman named Yvaine.
Witches and the Princes of Stormhold are also hunting for Yvaine.
Meanwhile, Tristan tries to get her back to Wall with him before
Victoria's birthday, the deadline for her offer.
The film was released to positive reviews and grossed
$137 million on a $70–88.5 million budget.
In 2008 it won the Hugo Award for Best Dramatic Presentation, Long Form.
It was released on DVD, Blu-ray and HD DVD on 18 December 2007.
The film explores themes of witch, new love, based on
novel or book, kingdom, transformation.
The tone is emotional.